<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aalto | studio any</title>
    <link>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/website-hugo-academic/tag/aalto/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://cmiltiadis.github.io/website-hugo-academic/tag/aalto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Aalto</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/website-hugo-academic/media/icon_hu4964246c05a61ea2dde1a8350b549fed_585_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Aalto</title>
      <link>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/website-hugo-academic/tag/aalto/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space-Time-Craft: Notions of digital craft and design practice in contemporary research</title>
      <link>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/website-hugo-academic/event/space-time-craft/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/website-hugo-academic/event/space-time-craft/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presenters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Benedict Singleton  (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rivalstrategy.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;RIVAL STRATEGY&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; keynote)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lucy Davis (Aalto ARTS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Constantinos Miltiadis  (Aalto ARTS &amp;ndash; space-time-craft)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Event organizer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Bassam El Baroni&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--
### Space-Time-Craft: Notions of digital craft and design practice in contemporary research 

What is contemporary craft? 
Unlike vernacular notions of craft -- involving situated knowledges of a place and its available material which are cultivated over generations and performed by masters -- the notion of craft in our times poses a challenge, even more so in the context of research. 
The presentation will discuss notions of digital craft based on my research that investigates virtual space and movement *through exploratory design experimentation*. 
While virtual environments are ubiquitous, digital media like virtual reality and videogames are lacking formal foundations or discourses pertaining to their design and development.
In my work I approach virtual space as a &#39;contemporary material&#39;, something that necessitates practical experimentation for investigating its capacities and potentials. I develop experimental prototypes to investigate virtual environments that are experienceable, however, impossible to construct or come across in the physical world. 
The aim of this practice is twofold: the exploration of the design space of such media through experienceable artifacts which also serve as research objects, parallel to the investigation of what is possible to experience. 
Lastly, the presentation will discuss current difficulties in admitting design prototypes, and especially &#39;playable artifacts&#39; as research objects. 

--&gt;
&lt;!--
20 minute presentation about how you think of your practice and research as a craft, a well contextualised short presentation that is not too dense and high speed otherwise their minds will explode and we don&#39;t want to clean up brain matter in the classroom. The presentation is part of the course Thinking Practices in Art and Media, the day you&#39;ll be presenting in will feature another short presentation by Lucy Davies and a Keynote by Benedict Singleton around craftiness as a main concern of art and design
--&gt;
&lt;!--


What is contemporary craft? 

As &#39;craft&#39; we usually identify colloquial practices 

Digital space 

The talk will discuss ongoing research pertaining to digital navigable space: virtual environments that allow for movement. 

# Bio 
**Constantinos Miltiadis** is a transdisciplinary architect and researcher; occasionally also programmer, media artist, curator, teacher, and librarian. His work is concerned with aesthetic phenomena between technology and culture, and his primary research investigates the design and experience of spatiotemporal navigable environments _inconstructible_ in the physical world, specific to and experienceable through digital media. He holds a diploma of architecture engineering from NTU-Athens, and a postgraduate degree on architecture and information from the Chair for CAAD ETH Zurich, with additional studies in computer music at IEM KU Graz. Constantinos’ work has been presented in seminars and exhibitions, published in conferences, journals as well as by international press. He has developed and taught courses on creative programming and experimental VR videogame design in academic contexts as well as conferences and art festivals. Between 2015 and 2019 Constantinos was assistant professor at the Institute of Architecture and Media of TU Graz. Since 2019 he is a doctoral researcher at the Dept. of Design, and the Dept. of Architecture at the School of ARTS at Aalto University in Helsinki.

Personal website: [www⁄studioany.com](http://studioany.com/)
--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The situation of space in contemporary media environments</title>
      <link>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/website-hugo-academic/event/the-situation-of-space-in-contemporary-media-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 16:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/website-hugo-academic/event/the-situation-of-space-in-contemporary-media-environments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;space-writing-within-architectures-expanded-field&#34;&gt;Space-Writing Within Architecture’s Expanded Field &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Space, as the substrate that conditions design and architecture is often taken for granted. Through a brief archeology of the evolution of spatial concepts from Greek mathematics through Renaissance perspective and 20th century physics, this talk intends to present how design-space is a culturally embedded “ideology” that adheres more to tradition rather than to any current scientific theory. Contemporary space-making media however can allow for us to experiment with and explore perceivable spaces beyond the traditions of design, as well as of what is constructible in physical reality, requiring thus a new set of conventions for engagement with space. Akin to writing spaces rather than designing in space, “choropoietic media” from drawing to videogames, VR and spatial audio, challenge us in considering an “expanded field” of architecture and spatial praxis, while providing vehicles for uncovering latent spectra of aesthetic experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Constantinos Miltiadis (&lt;a href=&#34;http://studioany.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;studioany.com/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Constantinos Miltiadis is a transdisciplinary architect, whose research and practice focus on virtual spatiotemporal environments, as a means of expanding the scope of architecture and its aesthetics. He has studied architecture at NTU-Athens, at the Chair for Computer Aided Architectural Design of ETH Zurich, and pursued studies in computer music at the Institute of Electronic Music of Kunst Uni Graz. His work has been presented in exhibitions, seminars, published in academic conferences as well as by international press, and received awards in international competitions. He has taught creative programming and experimental computation in academic contexts, as well as in conferences and art festivals. In addition, he was founder and curator of the “&lt;em&gt;IAM Open Lectures&lt;/em&gt;” and co-founder of “&lt;em&gt;Tabletalks on Architecture&lt;/em&gt;” as well as of the experimental electronic music event series . Between 2015 and 2019 he has been assistant professor at the Institute of Architecture and Media of TU Graz, while currently he is a doctoral student between the departments of Design and Architecture at Aalto ARTS, part of the Experience Platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;spatial-aestheticsin-auditive-media-composition&#34;&gt;Spatial Aesthetics in Auditive Media Composition&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the cases both of music and of science, detachment involved the use of mechanical aids: scientic instruments helped discover a world, musical instruments to build one (D. Burrows)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We as composers and sound artists have never confronted a machine of the collective, networked, and externally defined media perception design as we experience it today. So what do we share with our audience, the engineers and scientists working on perceptions in media spaces, and how can we still detect potential for aesthetic experiences and make them useful for the acoustic arts? It seems unavoidable that this question causes us to fall back on our ears and the aesthetic reflection of what is experienced and experienceable in situ. Spatialization is the synthesis of spaces and spatial properties of sounds for audiences using numerous loudspeakers. Although one of the most important developments in music within the past century it is still an area of confusion and fundamentally different opinions between researchers, sound engineers, composers, and audiences. Great advantages in computer and audio technology have not necessarily yet led to similarly greater artistic advances in spatialization strategies and concepts within the past decades when compared with pioneering electro-acoustic music in the 1950s, in which visions of sculptural sound phenomena from the 1930s were firstly created and publicly performed. Moreover, as spatial computer music matures and consolidates within institutions and organizations, it is increasingly involving 3D audio systems which can create auditory virtual environments (AVEs). Quite likely in the very near future AVEs will be part of many people’s everyday life, e.g. in cars, working spaces, intelligent homes, concert halls and computer games. The emerging general question is, who creates these ‘virtual’ environments with which intention and how can music, sound art and sound design aesthetically contribute to this reality with their own strategies?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gerriet K. Sharma (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gksh.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gksh.net&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gerriet K. Sharma is a composer and sound artist. He studied Media Art at the Academy of Media Arts Cologne and composition/computer music at the University of Music and Performing Arts Graz. In 2016 he completed his doctorate at the scientific-artistic doctoral school Graz. His thesis is titled “Composing Sculptural Sound Phenomena in Computer Music”. Within the last 15 years he was deeply involved in spatialization of electroacoustic compositions in Ambisonics and Wave-Field Synthesis and transformation into 3D-soundsculptures. From 2009 to 2015 he was curator of “signale-graz” concert series for electroacoustic music, algorithmic composition, radio art and performance at the MUMUTH Graz. His works were presented and premiered at festivals in Europe and abroad. Scholarships by the German Academic Exchange Programme (DAAD) in 2007 and 2009. In 2008 he was awarded with the German Sound Art Award. In 2007 and 2010 he was Artist in Residence at Pact Zollverein Essen working on his concept of sculptural sound projection and formation. Within his Residency at the Institute of Musicology Wuerzburg 2011 – 2013 he conceived and established the Atelier for Sound Research. In spring 2014 he was composer in residence at ZKM Karlsruhe/Germany. 2015 – 2018 he was senior researcher and composer within the three year artistic research project “Orchestrating Space by Icosahedral Loudspeaker” (OSIL) funded by the Austrian Science Fund (FWF). He had been appointed as DAAD Edgar Varèse guest-professor at Electronic Music Studio, Audio communication (AK), TU Berlin for WS 2017/18. In 2019/20 he is visiting professor (Music and Technology) at IKG DART doctorate school Madrid. Publications in international journals and books on spatial practices and sound. “Aural Sculpturality. Spatio-temporal Phenomena within Auditive Media Techniques” was published by ZKM in 2019, his text “Surrounded by Immersion – Means of Post-Democratic Warfare” was released in the book Ultra Black of Music by Mille Plateaux in March 2020. He lives in Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Constantinos and Gerriet are founding members of the Special Interest Group on “Spatial Aesthetics and Artificial Environments” (2019) as part of the Society for Artistic Research (SAR).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
