<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>craft | studio any</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/craft/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/craft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>craft</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu4964246c05a61ea2dde1a8350b549fed_585_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>craft</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/craft/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space-Time-Craft: Notions of digital craft and design practice in contemporary research</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/space-time-craft/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/event/space-time-craft/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presenters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Benedict Singleton  (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rivalstrategy.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;RIVAL STRATEGY&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; keynote)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lucy Davis (Aalto ARTS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Constantinos Miltiadis  (Aalto ARTS &amp;ndash; space-time-craft)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Event organizer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Bassam El Baroni&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--
### Space-Time-Craft: Notions of digital craft and design practice in contemporary research 

What is contemporary craft? 
Unlike vernacular notions of craft -- involving situated knowledges of a place and its available material which are cultivated over generations and performed by masters -- the notion of craft in our times poses a challenge, even more so in the context of research. 
The presentation will discuss notions of digital craft based on my research that investigates virtual space and movement *through exploratory design experimentation*. 
While virtual environments are ubiquitous, digital media like virtual reality and videogames are lacking formal foundations or discourses pertaining to their design and development.
In my work I approach virtual space as a &#39;contemporary material&#39;, something that necessitates practical experimentation for investigating its capacities and potentials. I develop experimental prototypes to investigate virtual environments that are experienceable, however, impossible to construct or come across in the physical world. 
The aim of this practice is twofold: the exploration of the design space of such media through experienceable artifacts which also serve as research objects, parallel to the investigation of what is possible to experience. 
Lastly, the presentation will discuss current difficulties in admitting design prototypes, and especially &#39;playable artifacts&#39; as research objects. 

--&gt;
&lt;!--
20 minute presentation about how you think of your practice and research as a craft, a well contextualised short presentation that is not too dense and high speed otherwise their minds will explode and we don&#39;t want to clean up brain matter in the classroom. The presentation is part of the course Thinking Practices in Art and Media, the day you&#39;ll be presenting in will feature another short presentation by Lucy Davies and a Keynote by Benedict Singleton around craftiness as a main concern of art and design
--&gt;
&lt;!--


What is contemporary craft? 

As &#39;craft&#39; we usually identify colloquial practices 

Digital space 

The talk will discuss ongoing research pertaining to digital navigable space: virtual environments that allow for movement. 

# Bio 
**Constantinos Miltiadis** is a transdisciplinary architect and researcher; occasionally also programmer, media artist, curator, teacher, and librarian. His work is concerned with aesthetic phenomena between technology and culture, and his primary research investigates the design and experience of spatiotemporal navigable environments _inconstructible_ in the physical world, specific to and experienceable through digital media. He holds a diploma of architecture engineering from NTU-Athens, and a postgraduate degree on architecture and information from the Chair for CAAD ETH Zurich, with additional studies in computer music at IEM KU Graz. Constantinos’ work has been presented in seminars and exhibitions, published in conferences, journals as well as by international press. He has developed and taught courses on creative programming and experimental VR videogame design in academic contexts as well as conferences and art festivals. Between 2015 and 2019 Constantinos was assistant professor at the Institute of Architecture and Media of TU Graz. Since 2019 he is a doctoral researcher at the Dept. of Design, and the Dept. of Architecture at the School of ARTS at Aalto University in Helsinki.

Personal website: [www⁄studioany.com](http://studioany.com/)
--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
