<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>game studies | studio any</title>
    <link>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/tag/game-studies/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/tag/game-studies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>game studies</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/media/icon_hu4964246c05a61ea2dde1a8350b549fed_585_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>game studies</title>
      <link>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/tag/game-studies/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Architecture and SpaceTimeCraft</title>
      <link>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/project/spacetimecraft/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/project/spacetimecraft/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Long-term transdisciplinary research project on virtual architecture.
The project investigates the aesthetic experience in virtual spatiotemporal environments that cannot be reproduced in physical reality, through integrative design research.
It is pursued through mixed methods including prototyping, experimental gamemaking, teaching experimental course curricula, media archeology, presenting and publishing; and it interfaces with discourse fields including architecture, game studies, design research, media studies, and artistic research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project started following the development of &lt;a href=&#34;../project-anywhere&#34;&gt;project Anywhere&lt;/a&gt; at the Chair for CAAD at ETH Zurich in 2014. It continued through teaching the experimental course &lt;a href=&#34;https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/tag/vsms&#34;&gt;Virtual Spaces Master Studio&lt;/a&gt; on VR game design for architects developed and taught at the Institute of Architecture and Media at TU Graz in 2016 and 2017, as well as other short intensive &lt;a href=&#34;https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/tag/workshop&#34;&gt;workshops&lt;/a&gt;.
In late 2019 the project developed into a doctoral research project at Aalto University, School of Arts, expected in 2025, titled: &lt;em&gt;SpaceTimeCraft: Integrative Research through Design into the Experience of Virtual Navigation&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is a catalog of related publications and presentations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From player representation to enactive presence: The case of &#34;boomer shooters&#34;</title>
      <link>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/event/from-player-representation-to-enactive-presence-the-case-of-boomer-shooters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/event/from-player-representation-to-enactive-presence-the-case-of-boomer-shooters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;presentation-abstract&#34;&gt;Presentation abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just forget it. You know they are demons; we know they are demons; we both want to shoot them in the face. Let&amp;rsquo;s just go (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vsoVQWnSOfM&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hugo Martin 2016&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The videogame medium generated novel forms of storytelling and character representation, matters that were discussed in length in the context of game studies. This proposal, concerns a persistent and sizeable part of videogames that offer neither stories, nor player-character representations per se. Just action journeys. Such game experiences often evade analytical lenses due to difficulties of accounting for nothing but moment-to-moment action in virtual space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These cases are not about how the protagonist is represented (who is usually silent) nor a storyline (which often is a necessary wrapper around a sequence of predictably escalating challenges). What they celebrate instead are affective non-verbal aesthetics of virtual enaction.A prevalent example of this type is the ‘&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dXCOKpJcYZU&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;boomer/movement shooter&lt;/a&gt;’ genre, a resurgence of the co-called ‘old school,’ ‘mindless’ first-person shooters, which was kickstarted with the modern reboot of Doom (id Software) in 2016.&lt;br&gt;
Games of this genre often display contempt toward high brow or consistent narratives. Here, any potential or necessary injection of story elements is rather utilitarian, serving as pacing break, setting up the gameworld, and empowering the player, often toward the ridiculous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Just forget it [&amp;hellip;] Let&amp;rsquo;s just go,&amp;rdquo; Doom director Hugo Martin remarked on its ridiculous staging. Whether, Nazis, demons, aliens or other necessary evils, what these games suggest is a mode of representation through identification with what the protagonist &lt;em&gt;can practically do&lt;/em&gt; in the gameworld, and less than, or even against notions such as who they are, or why they do. They boil down to enactive representation: the mastery of actions like jumping, dashing, sliding and shooting, which define and set apart the protagonist in both worlds &amp;ndash; what Martin termed &amp;lsquo;Doom dance.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;workshop-programme&#34;&gt;Workshop programme&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;tuesday-august-29&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday August 29&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;09.30 Registration and Introductions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10.00-11.30   &lt;strong&gt;Representation, Imagination and Fiction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stacie Friend&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;11.30-13.00&lt;/em&gt;  Lunch break&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;13.00-13.45   &lt;strong&gt;Representations of the Immaterial Through Player as a Prop in Video Games&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maciej Jemioł&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;13.45-14.30  &lt;strong&gt;From Player Representation to Enactive Presence: The Case of ‘Boomer Shooters’&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Constantinos Mitiadis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;14.30-15.15  &lt;strong&gt;The Game of Video Game Objects&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesper Juul&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;15.15-15.45&lt;/em&gt;  Coffee break&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15.45-16.30  &lt;strong&gt;The Epistemic Power of Perception In Virtual Worlds and Virtual Games&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph Larse&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;16.30-17.15   &lt;strong&gt;Ludofictionality&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Sageng&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;17.15-18.00  &lt;strong&gt;SNES is my Co-Author??? Authorship, Videogames, and Generative Glitches&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nathan Wildman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;20.15  Conference dinner at “Madklubben”, St. Kongensgade 66&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wednesday-august-30&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday August 30&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;09.30-11.00  &lt;strong&gt;Cybersemantics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peter Pagin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11.00-11.45 –  &lt;strong&gt;Diegetic versus Deictic Fiction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rune Klevjer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11.45-13.00  Lunch break&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;13.00-13.45  &lt;strong&gt;Perceiving Represented Gameworlds: Actual, Fictional, and Imaginative Perceptions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nele van der Mossalen &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;13.45-14.30  &lt;strong&gt;The Challenge of Genius Loci and Spatial Representation in Virtual Worlds&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniele Monaco &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;14.30-15.15 &lt;strong&gt;Reasoning in Computerized and Non-Computerized Games&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ida Jorgensen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15.15-15.45  Coffee break&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15.45-16.30  &lt;strong&gt;Against Metaphysical Interpretations of VR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grant Tavinor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;16.30-17.15 &lt;strong&gt;Why VR Does Not Involve Picture Perception – a Gibsonian Account&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edward Baggs, Paweł Grabarczyk and Zuzanna Rucińska&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;17.15-18.00 – &lt;strong&gt;Veridical Representation through Exaggeration in “Hans Christian and I”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dooley Murphy&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other than Text: Media Used in Game Studies Publications</title>
      <link>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/publication/23-digra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 14:23:09 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/publication/23-digra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;publication-history&#34;&gt;Publication history&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I originally wrote this paper in late 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was submitted in January 2022 for the conference &amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Architectural Continuum: Choropoietic media and post-physical-world spatial aesthetics</title>
      <link>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/event/continuum-cologne/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 10:00:03 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/event/continuum-cologne/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Workshop organized by Marc Bonner, DFG fellow at Universität zu Köln.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Event description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The international conference will be held in context of the DFG funded research project “Open-World-Structures: Architecture, City- and Landscape in Computer Games” (Bonner 2017-2020) and addresses the matter of (1) architecture in game worlds in the sense of its media specific spatialization, architectural layouts and the role of architecture, as well as (2) the architecture of computer games themselves in the sense of systematics, structures and media specific logics between algorithms and databases – worldbuilding from a different angle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, the participants will thematise aesthetics of reception as well as aesthetics of production and approach the complex constitution of computer games from a wide range of disciplines – from Media and Game Studies to Art History, Sound Studies to Architecture, Design to Phenomenology and Embodiment, as well as Spatial Theory and Cultural Studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim of the conference is to channel multi-disciplinary approaches and current research projects to fuel an interest towards an understanding of computer games as spatial, architectural or world phenomena within the current digital media culture. Furthermore, it is to explore and discuss concepts and methodologies from other disciplines and the potential transfer as useful tools in Game Studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;workshop-programme&#34;&gt;Workshop programme&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;monday-031819&#34;&gt;Monday, 03/18/19&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Distant Agricultural Splendor: National Identity, Agricultural Labor, and Space in Farming Simulator (Derek Price) 10:45 a.m.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taking a Breath of the Wild – Paidiatic Spaces and Practices Off the Ludic Grid (Cornelia Janina Schnaars) 11:05 a.m.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feels Right – How Atmospheres of the Past Satisfy Expectations of Authenticity (Felix Zimmermann) 11:25 a.m.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Virtual Space and Video Game Photography: Towards a Socio-Political Reading of In-Game Photography (Vladimir Rizov) 12:00 p.m.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The World Machine: Self-Reflexive Worldmaking in OneShot (Theresa Krampe) 12:20 p.m.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Towards an Operationalized Definition of Procedural Representation (Michal Švarný) 12:40 p.m.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Welcoming Speech / Introduction (Marc Bonner) 1:30 p.m.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Protean Spaces. On the Aesthetics of Reconfiguring Game Spaces (Hans-Joachim Backe) 2:00 p.m.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning from Las Vegas … About Video Games and Virtual Reality Experiences (Gundolf S. Freyermuth) 2:45 p.m.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Labyrinth (Rolf F. Nohr) 3:45 p.m.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personal and Cinematic Landscapes in Games (Rune Klevjer) 4:30 p.m.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ludoforming (Espen Aarseth) 5:30 p.m.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tuesday-031919&#34;&gt;Tuesday, 03/19/19&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Borderless Sound (Marcus Erbe) 10:00 a.m.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;»I love how you can see the bottom of the universe from this room…« The Inside-Out-Architecture of Davey Wreden’s The Beginner’s Guide (Benjamin Beil) 11:00 a.m.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Interior of Video Games (Thomas Hensel) 11:45 a.m.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two Ways to Dwell: Hestial and Hermetic Dwelling in Digital Game Worlds (Daniel Vella) 1:30 p.m.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ‘Lived Spaces’ of Computer Games (Stephan Günzel) 2:15 p.m.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sense of Being Here: 3D Spaces Between Vision and Haptics (Carolin Höfler) 3:15 p.m.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Architectural Continuum – Choropoietic Media and Post-Physical-World Spatial Aesthetics (Constantinos Miltiadis) 4:00 p.m.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dreaming in the Witch House (Thomas Hawranke) 4:45 p.m.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Round Up Discussion 5:45 p.m.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the hypotheses which lie at the bases of game design: flat earthers and post-physical navigable environments</title>
      <link>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/event/hypotheses-krakow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/event/hypotheses-krakow/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the Implied Player: Transgression and Contingency in Digital Games</title>
      <link>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/event/beyond-the-implied-player-transgression-and-contingency-in-digital-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/event/beyond-the-implied-player-transgression-and-contingency-in-digital-games/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!--
abstract 
https://www.researchgate.net/publication/328174581_Beyond_the_Implied_Player_Transgression_and_Contingency_in_Digital_Games

https://gespielt.hypotheses.org/2009

--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Reality, Videogames, Architecture and Education - From utopian drawings to inconstructible navigable environments</title>
      <link>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/publication/18-ecaade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/publication/18-ecaade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Miltiadis, Constantinos. ‘Virtual Reality, Videogames, Architecture and Education. From Utopian Drawings to Inconstructible Navigable Environments’. In &lt;em&gt;Computing for a Better Tomorrow - Proceedings of the 36th ECAADe Conference&lt;/em&gt;, edited by A Kepczynska-Walczak and S Bialkowski, 2:815–24. Lodz, Poland: Lodz University of Technology, 2018. &lt;a href=&#34;http://papers.cumincad.org/cgi-bin/works/paper/ecaade2018_366&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;http://papers.cumincad.org/cgi-bin/works/paper/ecaade2018_366&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Architectural Continuum</title>
      <link>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/event/continuum-architectonics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/event/continuum-architectonics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;event-description&#34;&gt;Event description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Space – in particular architectural and urban space – is always both real and virtual. For human beings, space is a construct of its perception via the body, but it is also culturally and socially determined as “relational space.” Architectural and urban spaces are inherently shaped by human beings: by their senses, by their perception, and by their cultural and social bonds. We experience these spaces as “real” and contingent, despite all possible false perceptions that might deceive us. They are an extension of our body – as well as related to the neurological, embodied mind – and are tied to its limitations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While traditional forms of virtuality such as movies and literature can only partially overcome these ties and boundaries – bound as they are to sight, sound, or our sense of fantasy – new digital tools and forms of immersive virtuality can reveal new orders of experience, allowing an interaction with this space. This interaction even partially allows one to design this space. At least one is either asked to perform tasks – play – or can replicate reality via simulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the latest at this point, one must question the nature of the relationship between “virtual reality” and “reality,” in particular regarding the experience and the design of space, and thus in relation to architecture. Is the designed virtual space a metaphor for real space and thus only a translation of it into virtual space, or is it more than that? Perhaps a transformation or extension of it? And what is different between these two, if there are any differences?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term “architectonics” (Architektonik) refers to the structure and nature of this space and thus to the threshold between architecture, either as system and structure or process. As such, architecture is either a metaphor (as discussed by Kant) – e.g. software-architecture – or a design process, with inherent methods and a specific spatial knowledge, which can be applied to the construction of virtual space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Architecture and town planning are disciplines based on design that create real and virtual spaces: rooms, buildings, towns, worlds. The process of design itself has always comprised a “virtual space” spanning the contingency of reality, with all its restrictions: the act of design itself – between making and thinking – and the implementation of the project in a real context, with a constant feedback loop between these different stages. The introduction of computers in the design process in the 1990s has significantly extended this space and created new and closer connections between reality and virtuality, which have only recently started to transform architecture and the act of design through algorithms and “design to production.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This “virtual space” of design has two implications for our discussion: on the one hand, despite decades of investigations via design theory, it remains a terra incognita, which reflects the Janus-faced nature of architecture between art and science; on the other, architecture and urbanism have traditionally fetishized this virtual space of the project – as utopia – not least because of the many oppositions to its ideals by clients, politics, costs, and so forth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This raises two questions that we would like to address in this round table/conference: Starting from these concurrent virtual spaces – architecture/video games/simulations – what can architecture learn from new virtual realities, in terms of its nature and of the act of design, and what can be the specific contribution of architecture both to the design of virtual spaces and their understanding? What can thus the contribution of architects to this new order of the virtual be, in the field of video games – including the aspects of gaming and narration – , serious games, or in the field of simulations, which allow for measurement and prediction (e.g. smart cities)? Can the architect apply their specific spatial abilities and the capacity to construct narratives around projects in this virtual context? And inversely, what can architecture and urbanism learn from this new virtual reality in all of its implications? Is there something of the design of virtual spaces in games or simulations that can be implemented in architecture and urbanism, in order to improve its efficiency or its sustainability, as well as to better understand the processes and nature of design?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, we must ask ourselves if the ubiquity of this virtual order represents a danger for architecture and urbanism, ushering in greater distance to the human “body” and “society,” for whom architecture has traditionally been constructed. Will these disciplines reduce their social and cultural impact through building virtual utopias, in which human beings and social ties will be simulated or mimicked – and thus lost? And is this euphoria for the potential of digital technologies not leading us again to naïve optimism, which in turn distracts us from real problems and leads architecture and urbanism to further abstraction from “reality?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to address these questions in a lively discussion with experts from different fields, most of whom hold a degree in architecture. Besides seven invited speakers, there are two more positions open to individuals with different disciplinary backgrounds – game theory, philosophy, architecture, history of technology, etc. – interested in these questions and ideally with a background in architecture. These will be selected via an open call for papers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organization: Andri Gerber, Institute Urban Landscape, ZHAW Winterthur, in collaboration with Werner Oechslin, Stiftung Bibliothek Werner Oechslin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;event-programme&#34;&gt;Event Programme&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andri Gerber (Institute Urban Landscape, ZHAW)&lt;br&gt;
Welcome/Introduction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stefano Gualeni (University of Malta)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.game.edu.mt/blog/architectonics-of-virtual-spaces/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;BIG TROUBLE in Little Cities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ekim Tan (Play the City)&lt;br&gt;
City Gaming&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James Delaney (BlockWorks)&lt;br&gt;
Architectonic of Virtual Space&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luke Caspar Pearson (Bartlett School of Architecture)&lt;br&gt;
Videogame Urbanism: rethinking speculative architecture projects through the design of virtual game spaces&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stephan Günzel (University of Applied Sciences Europe)&lt;br&gt;
The ‘Lived Spaces’ of Computer Games&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ulrich Götz (Zurich University of the Arts, ZHdK)&lt;br&gt;
The Design of Game Spaces, Caught Between Demands of the Virtual and References to the Real&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Philipp Schaerer (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.philippschaerer.ch&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;www.philippschaerer.ch&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;br&gt;
Built Images. Experimental and visual compositional techniques&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nicole Stoecklmayr (scenesofarchitecture.com)&lt;br&gt;
Parallel Perspectives: Experiencing Architecture on Screens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Constantinos Miltiadis (TU Graz)&lt;br&gt;
The Architectural Continuum&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Final discussion&lt;br&gt;
Johannes Binotto (HSLU)&lt;br&gt;
Philippe Koch (Institute Urban Landscape, ZHAW)&lt;br&gt;
Amadeo Sarbach (ZHAW)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Werner Oechslin (Stiftung Bibliothek Werner Oechslin)&lt;br&gt;
Guided visit through the library&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
