<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>digital spatial media | studio any</title>
    <link>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/tag/digital-spatial-media/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/tag/digital-spatial-media/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>digital spatial media</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 16:25:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/media/icon_hu4964246c05a61ea2dde1a8350b549fed_585_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>digital spatial media</title>
      <link>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/tag/digital-spatial-media/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The situation of space in contemporary media environments</title>
      <link>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/event/the-situation-of-space-in-contemporary-media-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 16:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/event/the-situation-of-space-in-contemporary-media-environments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;space-writing-within-architectures-expanded-field&#34;&gt;Space-Writing Within Architecture’s Expanded Field &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Space, as the substrate that conditions design and architecture is often taken for granted. Through a brief archeology of the evolution of spatial concepts from Greek mathematics through Renaissance perspective and 20th century physics, this talk intends to present how design-space is a culturally embedded “ideology” that adheres more to tradition rather than to any current scientific theory. Contemporary space-making media however can allow for us to experiment with and explore perceivable spaces beyond the traditions of design, as well as of what is constructible in physical reality, requiring thus a new set of conventions for engagement with space. Akin to writing spaces rather than designing in space, “choropoietic media” from drawing to videogames, VR and spatial audio, challenge us in considering an “expanded field” of architecture and spatial praxis, while providing vehicles for uncovering latent spectra of aesthetic experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Constantinos Miltiadis (&lt;a href=&#34;http://studioany.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;studioany.com/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Constantinos Miltiadis is a transdisciplinary architect, whose research and practice focus on virtual spatiotemporal environments, as a means of expanding the scope of architecture and its aesthetics. He has studied architecture at NTU-Athens, at the Chair for Computer Aided Architectural Design of ETH Zurich, and pursued studies in computer music at the Institute of Electronic Music of Kunst Uni Graz. His work has been presented in exhibitions, seminars, published in academic conferences as well as by international press, and received awards in international competitions. He has taught creative programming and experimental computation in academic contexts, as well as in conferences and art festivals. In addition, he was founder and curator of the “&lt;em&gt;IAM Open Lectures&lt;/em&gt;” and co-founder of “&lt;em&gt;Tabletalks on Architecture&lt;/em&gt;” as well as of the experimental electronic music event series . Between 2015 and 2019 he has been assistant professor at the Institute of Architecture and Media of TU Graz, while currently he is a doctoral student between the departments of Design and Architecture at Aalto ARTS, part of the Experience Platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;spatial-aestheticsin-auditive-media-composition&#34;&gt;Spatial Aesthetics in Auditive Media Composition&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the cases both of music and of science, detachment involved the use of mechanical aids: scientic instruments helped discover a world, musical instruments to build one (D. Burrows)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We as composers and sound artists have never confronted a machine of the collective, networked, and externally defined media perception design as we experience it today. So what do we share with our audience, the engineers and scientists working on perceptions in media spaces, and how can we still detect potential for aesthetic experiences and make them useful for the acoustic arts? It seems unavoidable that this question causes us to fall back on our ears and the aesthetic reflection of what is experienced and experienceable in situ. Spatialization is the synthesis of spaces and spatial properties of sounds for audiences using numerous loudspeakers. Although one of the most important developments in music within the past century it is still an area of confusion and fundamentally different opinions between researchers, sound engineers, composers, and audiences. Great advantages in computer and audio technology have not necessarily yet led to similarly greater artistic advances in spatialization strategies and concepts within the past decades when compared with pioneering electro-acoustic music in the 1950s, in which visions of sculptural sound phenomena from the 1930s were firstly created and publicly performed. Moreover, as spatial computer music matures and consolidates within institutions and organizations, it is increasingly involving 3D audio systems which can create auditory virtual environments (AVEs). Quite likely in the very near future AVEs will be part of many people’s everyday life, e.g. in cars, working spaces, intelligent homes, concert halls and computer games. The emerging general question is, who creates these ‘virtual’ environments with which intention and how can music, sound art and sound design aesthetically contribute to this reality with their own strategies?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gerriet K. Sharma (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gksh.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gksh.net&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gerriet K. Sharma is a composer and sound artist. He studied Media Art at the Academy of Media Arts Cologne and composition/computer music at the University of Music and Performing Arts Graz. In 2016 he completed his doctorate at the scientific-artistic doctoral school Graz. His thesis is titled “Composing Sculptural Sound Phenomena in Computer Music”. Within the last 15 years he was deeply involved in spatialization of electroacoustic compositions in Ambisonics and Wave-Field Synthesis and transformation into 3D-soundsculptures. From 2009 to 2015 he was curator of “signale-graz” concert series for electroacoustic music, algorithmic composition, radio art and performance at the MUMUTH Graz. His works were presented and premiered at festivals in Europe and abroad. Scholarships by the German Academic Exchange Programme (DAAD) in 2007 and 2009. In 2008 he was awarded with the German Sound Art Award. In 2007 and 2010 he was Artist in Residence at Pact Zollverein Essen working on his concept of sculptural sound projection and formation. Within his Residency at the Institute of Musicology Wuerzburg 2011 – 2013 he conceived and established the Atelier for Sound Research. In spring 2014 he was composer in residence at ZKM Karlsruhe/Germany. 2015 – 2018 he was senior researcher and composer within the three year artistic research project “Orchestrating Space by Icosahedral Loudspeaker” (OSIL) funded by the Austrian Science Fund (FWF). He had been appointed as DAAD Edgar Varèse guest-professor at Electronic Music Studio, Audio communication (AK), TU Berlin for WS 2017/18. In 2019/20 he is visiting professor (Music and Technology) at IKG DART doctorate school Madrid. Publications in international journals and books on spatial practices and sound. “Aural Sculpturality. Spatio-temporal Phenomena within Auditive Media Techniques” was published by ZKM in 2019, his text “Surrounded by Immersion – Means of Post-Democratic Warfare” was released in the book Ultra Black of Music by Mille Plateaux in March 2020. He lives in Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Constantinos and Gerriet are founding members of the Special Interest Group on “Spatial Aesthetics and Artificial Environments” (2019) as part of the Society for Artistic Research (SAR).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Inconstructible: space writing within architecture’s expanded field</title>
      <link>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/event/the-inconstructible-space-writing-within-architectures-expanded-field/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/event/the-inconstructible-space-writing-within-architectures-expanded-field/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inconstructible Architectures</title>
      <link>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/event/inconstructible-architectures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/event/inconstructible-architectures/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the hypotheses which lie at the bases of game design: flat earthers and post-physical navigable environments</title>
      <link>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/event/hypotheses-krakow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/event/hypotheses-krakow/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Aesthetics of Presence in Inconstructible Spaces I &amp; II</title>
      <link>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/event/the-aesthetics-of-presence-in-inconstructible-spaces-i-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/event/the-aesthetics-of-presence-in-inconstructible-spaces-i-ii/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Architectural Continuum</title>
      <link>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/event/continuum-architectonics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cmiltiadis.github.io/cmiltiadis/website-hugo-academic/event/continuum-architectonics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;event-description&#34;&gt;Event description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Space – in particular architectural and urban space – is always both real and virtual. For human beings, space is a construct of its perception via the body, but it is also culturally and socially determined as “relational space.” Architectural and urban spaces are inherently shaped by human beings: by their senses, by their perception, and by their cultural and social bonds. We experience these spaces as “real” and contingent, despite all possible false perceptions that might deceive us. They are an extension of our body – as well as related to the neurological, embodied mind – and are tied to its limitations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While traditional forms of virtuality such as movies and literature can only partially overcome these ties and boundaries – bound as they are to sight, sound, or our sense of fantasy – new digital tools and forms of immersive virtuality can reveal new orders of experience, allowing an interaction with this space. This interaction even partially allows one to design this space. At least one is either asked to perform tasks – play – or can replicate reality via simulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the latest at this point, one must question the nature of the relationship between “virtual reality” and “reality,” in particular regarding the experience and the design of space, and thus in relation to architecture. Is the designed virtual space a metaphor for real space and thus only a translation of it into virtual space, or is it more than that? Perhaps a transformation or extension of it? And what is different between these two, if there are any differences?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term “architectonics” (Architektonik) refers to the structure and nature of this space and thus to the threshold between architecture, either as system and structure or process. As such, architecture is either a metaphor (as discussed by Kant) – e.g. software-architecture – or a design process, with inherent methods and a specific spatial knowledge, which can be applied to the construction of virtual space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Architecture and town planning are disciplines based on design that create real and virtual spaces: rooms, buildings, towns, worlds. The process of design itself has always comprised a “virtual space” spanning the contingency of reality, with all its restrictions: the act of design itself – between making and thinking – and the implementation of the project in a real context, with a constant feedback loop between these different stages. The introduction of computers in the design process in the 1990s has significantly extended this space and created new and closer connections between reality and virtuality, which have only recently started to transform architecture and the act of design through algorithms and “design to production.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This “virtual space” of design has two implications for our discussion: on the one hand, despite decades of investigations via design theory, it remains a terra incognita, which reflects the Janus-faced nature of architecture between art and science; on the other, architecture and urbanism have traditionally fetishized this virtual space of the project – as utopia – not least because of the many oppositions to its ideals by clients, politics, costs, and so forth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This raises two questions that we would like to address in this round table/conference: Starting from these concurrent virtual spaces – architecture/video games/simulations – what can architecture learn from new virtual realities, in terms of its nature and of the act of design, and what can be the specific contribution of architecture both to the design of virtual spaces and their understanding? What can thus the contribution of architects to this new order of the virtual be, in the field of video games – including the aspects of gaming and narration – , serious games, or in the field of simulations, which allow for measurement and prediction (e.g. smart cities)? Can the architect apply their specific spatial abilities and the capacity to construct narratives around projects in this virtual context? And inversely, what can architecture and urbanism learn from this new virtual reality in all of its implications? Is there something of the design of virtual spaces in games or simulations that can be implemented in architecture and urbanism, in order to improve its efficiency or its sustainability, as well as to better understand the processes and nature of design?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, we must ask ourselves if the ubiquity of this virtual order represents a danger for architecture and urbanism, ushering in greater distance to the human “body” and “society,” for whom architecture has traditionally been constructed. Will these disciplines reduce their social and cultural impact through building virtual utopias, in which human beings and social ties will be simulated or mimicked – and thus lost? And is this euphoria for the potential of digital technologies not leading us again to naïve optimism, which in turn distracts us from real problems and leads architecture and urbanism to further abstraction from “reality?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to address these questions in a lively discussion with experts from different fields, most of whom hold a degree in architecture. Besides seven invited speakers, there are two more positions open to individuals with different disciplinary backgrounds – game theory, philosophy, architecture, history of technology, etc. – interested in these questions and ideally with a background in architecture. These will be selected via an open call for papers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organization: Andri Gerber, Institute Urban Landscape, ZHAW Winterthur, in collaboration with Werner Oechslin, Stiftung Bibliothek Werner Oechslin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;event-programme&#34;&gt;Event Programme&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andri Gerber (Institute Urban Landscape, ZHAW)&lt;br&gt;
Welcome/Introduction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stefano Gualeni (University of Malta)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.game.edu.mt/blog/architectonics-of-virtual-spaces/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;BIG TROUBLE in Little Cities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ekim Tan (Play the City)&lt;br&gt;
City Gaming&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James Delaney (BlockWorks)&lt;br&gt;
Architectonic of Virtual Space&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luke Caspar Pearson (Bartlett School of Architecture)&lt;br&gt;
Videogame Urbanism: rethinking speculative architecture projects through the design of virtual game spaces&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stephan Günzel (University of Applied Sciences Europe)&lt;br&gt;
The ‘Lived Spaces’ of Computer Games&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ulrich Götz (Zurich University of the Arts, ZHdK)&lt;br&gt;
The Design of Game Spaces, Caught Between Demands of the Virtual and References to the Real&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Philipp Schaerer (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.philippschaerer.ch&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;www.philippschaerer.ch&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;br&gt;
Built Images. Experimental and visual compositional techniques&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nicole Stoecklmayr (scenesofarchitecture.com)&lt;br&gt;
Parallel Perspectives: Experiencing Architecture on Screens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Constantinos Miltiadis (TU Graz)&lt;br&gt;
The Architectural Continuum&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Final discussion&lt;br&gt;
Johannes Binotto (HSLU)&lt;br&gt;
Philippe Koch (Institute Urban Landscape, ZHAW)&lt;br&gt;
Amadeo Sarbach (ZHAW)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Werner Oechslin (Stiftung Bibliothek Werner Oechslin)&lt;br&gt;
Guided visit through the library&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
