<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>architecture | studio any</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/architecture/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/architecture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>architecture</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 14:23:09 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu4964246c05a61ea2dde1a8350b549fed_585_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>architecture</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/architecture/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>An open living archive for ACADIA</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/23-acadia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 14:23:09 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/23-acadia/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ACADIA Conference Archive</title>
      <link>https://example.com/project/acadia-archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 14:21:30 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/project/acadia-archive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In May 2023, I was awarded the inaugural &lt;a href=&#34;http://acadia.org/news/69P4TY&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ACADIA Cultural History Project Fellowship&lt;/a&gt; together with Hanan Kataw (Ph.D. Candidate, Harvard University), and Hayri Dortdivanlioglu (Ph.D. Candidate, Georgia Institute of Technology).&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fellowship entailed production of work related to the &amp;lsquo;archive&amp;rsquo; of ACADIA, which at the time was an Excel sheet listing all papers published between 1985 and 2020, and a cloud drive with PDFs of conference proceedings volumes and other publications of ACADIA (e.g. quarterlies, membership lists, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My proposal was to create an open-access archive to host all content published by ACADIA. Using the data available, I wrote a Python program to parse this information and generate entries for an archive implementing &lt;em&gt;Sandpoints&lt;/em&gt;, an open-source open-infrastructure framework for experimental publishing.
The archive contains entries for all papers (1488), authors (2057), conference proceedings (40), and editors (116), as well as a library with readily available proceedings PDFs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All archive contents are open access; all infrastructure and tools used to create this archive are open-souce; all data and original software used to create this archive are shared openly and documented at the archive website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, the ACADIA archive is hosted at &lt;em&gt;Sandpoints&lt;/em&gt;, courtesy of Marcell Mars, at &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.sandpoints.org/sandpoints/acadiaarchive-46619c43/archive/acadia/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://pages.sandpoints.org/sandpoints/acadiaarchive-46619c43/archive/acadia/&lt;/a&gt; and is planned to move to archive.acadia.org .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;contribute&#34;&gt;Contribute&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an open and living archive, the ACADIA archive welcomes contributions both in the form of maintenance and care for the archive itself as well as contributions making use of its contents and hypertextual publishing format. Some ideas for contributions include: corrections and ammendments to existing entries; contributions of biographies of ACADIA members and contributors; contributions of articles about ACADIA and its history as well as archeological or thematic syllabuses making use of its material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;archive-contents&#34;&gt;Archive contents&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Item&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Amount&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Issues&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ACADIA conference annual proceedings&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;40  + 1 issue about the archive&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Articles&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Peer reviewed proceedings articles (up to 2020)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1488&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Contributors&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Article authors&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2057&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Editors&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Proceedings (issue) editors&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;116 + 1 entry for archivist&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Library&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Library catalogue with downloadable ACADIA publications (note: metadata not finalized)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;140&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Constantinos Miltiadis: Data parsing, computational archive production, librarianship&lt;br&gt;
Marcell Mars: Technical support and web hosting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;http://acadia.org/news/69P4TY&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ACADIA Cultural History Project Fellowship Announcement&lt;/a&gt; and  &lt;a href=&#34;http://acadia.org/features/GVHMR9&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Announcing Recipients of the ACADIA Cultural History Fellowship
&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the Visual - A research curriculum for explorations in spatiotemporal environments</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/beyond-the-visual/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/beyond-the-visual/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Miltiadis, Constantinos, and Gerriet K. Sharma. ‘Beyond the Visual - A Research Curriculum for Explorations in Spatiotemporal Environments’. &lt;em&gt;Journal for Artistic Research&lt;/em&gt;, no. 24 (27 September 2021). &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchcatalogue.net/view/815001/815002&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.researchcatalogue.net/view/815001/815002&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CAAD Futures 2021: Design Imperatives - The future is Now</title>
      <link>https://example.com/project/caad-futures-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 13:12:53 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/project/caad-futures-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Co-chair and co-organizer for the 2021 iteration of the CAAD Futures international biannual conference, hosted remotely by the University of Southern California (USC).
Contributed to authoring the open call, reviewing contributions, curating and hosting the keynote panel sessions, and co-editing the proceedings volume of the conference published in 2022 by &lt;em&gt;Springer&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conference co-chairs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;David Gerber (main chair; USC)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Biayna Bogosian (USC; Florida International University)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evan Pantasis (IBI Group; USC)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alicia Nahmad (University of Calgary)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Constantinos Miltiadis (Aalto University)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- 
Conference co-chair, co-organizer, and host; co-curator of the keynote panel sessions;  co-writer of the conference open call; contribution reviewer; co-writer of the volume editorial.
--&gt; 
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Architectural Continuum</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/continuum-digital-cultures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/event/continuum-digital-cultures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- 
1.12.2024: digital cultures website doesnt work: available to buy 
paper titled “The architectural continuum” will be presented at the [Digital Cultures 2018 Conference](https://digitalculturesconference.org/) at the Leuphana University of Lüneburg, 19-22 of September 2018.  
Detailed conference schedule [[x](https://digitalculturesconference.org/files/2018/09/KCT18_Program_Abstracts.pdf)]  
Download abstract from researchgate [[x](https://www.researchgate.net/publication/327436853_The_Architectural_Continuum_Abstract)]
--&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;presentation-abstract&#34;&gt;Presentation abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Ουδείς αγεωμέτρητος εισήτω” reads the inscription believed to have marked the entrance of Plato’s Academy. Although often mistranslated, it’s literal meaning is: “Let no ungeometered person enter.” Plato addresses not geometers, but the geometered, as if mathematics were a practiced, embodied quality, and a modality of being, instead of mere knowledge. Indeed, Euclid’s rigorous axiomatic system, doubles also as a first formal scientific method, that Plato will employ as an instrument to better understand reality, while expecting from his students and guests the ability to employ the empirical sequential methodology of constructible geometry in their rhetoric. Mathematics thus, becomes a form of ideology. Centuries later, Alberti’s “De Pittura”, on mathematical perspective, bridges geometry with the experience of the world and initiates the scientific revolution. Cartesian rationalism will employ geometry to represent and understand the world, while Kant will advocate for “absolute space” as the petri dish of reality. In the millennia to come, Euclid’s geometry will become the most intuitive model of space. However, the search for a proof of his infamous fifth postulate, will trouble mathematicians for centuries. Gauss’ “Theorema Egregium” will provide a paradigm shift and alternative to Cartesian space, while his student Riemann, addressing the “hypotheses which lie at the bases of geometry” will generalize the theory for N-dimensions. Einstein will adopt such a geometry to theorize reality as spacetime, accounting for phenomena unheard of in Euclidean space, and providing the first significant rupture between visual space and reality. Meanwhile, video games become the most prominent entertainment medium and the field of game studies is established. Scholars will write on space; as the ‘raison d’être’ of games; as a parallel to architectural practices; and as a paradigm shift of this cultural medium coming of age. Space has indeed become the underlying substrate in both the production and consumption of games, with gameplay seen a spatial practice. From military flight simulators to contemporary videogames, ‘gameplay’ has been proven to develop and expand one’s spatial skills. Although architectural design is locked in a Euclidean paradigm, a few video games show our capacity to conceive and engage with spaces impossible to construct physically. Through a short historiography of the evolution of spatial concepts, this contribution intends to suggest the possibility of a Virtual Architecture. Based on both theory and experimental practice we will discuss sensible, postphysical-world navigable environments residing in the VR-video game medium, and the vast aesthetic potential stemming from their capacity to tap into currently latent spatial-cognitive abilities. As Van Schaik suggests, our ability to harness and cultivate “spatial intelligence” is the essence of architecture par excellence, and the well of its future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Architectural Continuum</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/continuum-architectonics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/event/continuum-architectonics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;event-description&#34;&gt;Event description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Space – in particular architectural and urban space – is always both real and virtual. For human beings, space is a construct of its perception via the body, but it is also culturally and socially determined as “relational space.” Architectural and urban spaces are inherently shaped by human beings: by their senses, by their perception, and by their cultural and social bonds. We experience these spaces as “real” and contingent, despite all possible false perceptions that might deceive us. They are an extension of our body – as well as related to the neurological, embodied mind – and are tied to its limitations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While traditional forms of virtuality such as movies and literature can only partially overcome these ties and boundaries – bound as they are to sight, sound, or our sense of fantasy – new digital tools and forms of immersive virtuality can reveal new orders of experience, allowing an interaction with this space. This interaction even partially allows one to design this space. At least one is either asked to perform tasks – play – or can replicate reality via simulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the latest at this point, one must question the nature of the relationship between “virtual reality” and “reality,” in particular regarding the experience and the design of space, and thus in relation to architecture. Is the designed virtual space a metaphor for real space and thus only a translation of it into virtual space, or is it more than that? Perhaps a transformation or extension of it? And what is different between these two, if there are any differences?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term “architectonics” (Architektonik) refers to the structure and nature of this space and thus to the threshold between architecture, either as system and structure or process. As such, architecture is either a metaphor (as discussed by Kant) – e.g. software-architecture – or a design process, with inherent methods and a specific spatial knowledge, which can be applied to the construction of virtual space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Architecture and town planning are disciplines based on design that create real and virtual spaces: rooms, buildings, towns, worlds. The process of design itself has always comprised a “virtual space” spanning the contingency of reality, with all its restrictions: the act of design itself – between making and thinking – and the implementation of the project in a real context, with a constant feedback loop between these different stages. The introduction of computers in the design process in the 1990s has significantly extended this space and created new and closer connections between reality and virtuality, which have only recently started to transform architecture and the act of design through algorithms and “design to production.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This “virtual space” of design has two implications for our discussion: on the one hand, despite decades of investigations via design theory, it remains a terra incognita, which reflects the Janus-faced nature of architecture between art and science; on the other, architecture and urbanism have traditionally fetishized this virtual space of the project – as utopia – not least because of the many oppositions to its ideals by clients, politics, costs, and so forth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This raises two questions that we would like to address in this round table/conference: Starting from these concurrent virtual spaces – architecture/video games/simulations – what can architecture learn from new virtual realities, in terms of its nature and of the act of design, and what can be the specific contribution of architecture both to the design of virtual spaces and their understanding? What can thus the contribution of architects to this new order of the virtual be, in the field of video games – including the aspects of gaming and narration – , serious games, or in the field of simulations, which allow for measurement and prediction (e.g. smart cities)? Can the architect apply their specific spatial abilities and the capacity to construct narratives around projects in this virtual context? And inversely, what can architecture and urbanism learn from this new virtual reality in all of its implications? Is there something of the design of virtual spaces in games or simulations that can be implemented in architecture and urbanism, in order to improve its efficiency or its sustainability, as well as to better understand the processes and nature of design?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, we must ask ourselves if the ubiquity of this virtual order represents a danger for architecture and urbanism, ushering in greater distance to the human “body” and “society,” for whom architecture has traditionally been constructed. Will these disciplines reduce their social and cultural impact through building virtual utopias, in which human beings and social ties will be simulated or mimicked – and thus lost? And is this euphoria for the potential of digital technologies not leading us again to naïve optimism, which in turn distracts us from real problems and leads architecture and urbanism to further abstraction from “reality?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to address these questions in a lively discussion with experts from different fields, most of whom hold a degree in architecture. Besides seven invited speakers, there are two more positions open to individuals with different disciplinary backgrounds – game theory, philosophy, architecture, history of technology, etc. – interested in these questions and ideally with a background in architecture. These will be selected via an open call for papers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organization: Andri Gerber, Institute Urban Landscape, ZHAW Winterthur, in collaboration with Werner Oechslin, Stiftung Bibliothek Werner Oechslin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;event-programme&#34;&gt;Event Programme&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andri Gerber (Institute Urban Landscape, ZHAW)&lt;br&gt;
Welcome/Introduction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stefano Gualeni (University of Malta)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.game.edu.mt/blog/architectonics-of-virtual-spaces/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;BIG TROUBLE in Little Cities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ekim Tan (Play the City)&lt;br&gt;
City Gaming&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James Delaney (BlockWorks)&lt;br&gt;
Architectonic of Virtual Space&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luke Caspar Pearson (Bartlett School of Architecture)&lt;br&gt;
Videogame Urbanism: rethinking speculative architecture projects through the design of virtual game spaces&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stephan Günzel (University of Applied Sciences Europe)&lt;br&gt;
The ‘Lived Spaces’ of Computer Games&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ulrich Götz (Zurich University of the Arts, ZHdK)&lt;br&gt;
The Design of Game Spaces, Caught Between Demands of the Virtual and References to the Real&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Philipp Schaerer (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.philippschaerer.ch&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;www.philippschaerer.ch&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;br&gt;
Built Images. Experimental and visual compositional techniques&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nicole Stoecklmayr (scenesofarchitecture.com)&lt;br&gt;
Parallel Perspectives: Experiencing Architecture on Screens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Constantinos Miltiadis (TU Graz)&lt;br&gt;
The Architectural Continuum&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Final discussion&lt;br&gt;
Johannes Binotto (HSLU)&lt;br&gt;
Philippe Koch (Institute Urban Landscape, ZHAW)&lt;br&gt;
Amadeo Sarbach (ZHAW)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Werner Oechslin (Stiftung Bibliothek Werner Oechslin)&lt;br&gt;
Guided visit through the library&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Architecture as a Complex Number</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/architecture-as-a-complex-number/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/event/architecture-as-a-complex-number/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://example.com/images/16-plexus-paris.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

Event organized by Pierre Cutellic in collaboration with AA n+1.&lt;br&gt;
AA n+1 gallery, Paris, November 16, 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The Plexus Project is an initiative to bring together the creative talent of different disciplines to share techniques, solve problems and build networks of collaboration. The events take place every month inviting young designers, architects, engineers, programmers, game designers and visual artists. This initiative is open to anyone in London that is looking for an informal place to network and learn about new methodologies and workflows.&lt;br&gt;
The event was initially called Bartlett Nexus and was created by Jose Sanchez, currently he co-curates it together with Manuel Jimenez Garcia, who joined the event organization in September of 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speakers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prof. Frederic Migayrou (UCL),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manuel Jimenez Garcia (UCL),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Constantinos Miltiadis (TU Graz), and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corneel Cannaerts (KU Leuven).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tabletalks on Architecture (2016-2017)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/project/16-tabletalks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 15:33:29 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/project/16-tabletalks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tabletalks on Architecture&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; was a lecture series produced by a group of university assistants at the Faculty of Architecture, TU Graz between 2016 and 2017.
The initiative was conceived as as means to foster current research and as a casual event outside of formal university structures where academics, students, and practicing architects can converge, engage, exchange, and discuss matters related to architecture and architectural research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founding members of the initiative include Constantinos Miltiadis, Diederik de Koning, Marcello Fantuz, Sophia Walk, and Christoph Braser.&lt;br&gt;
Graphic design by Lilly Hafner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tabletalks on Architecture&lt;/em&gt; ran between 2016 and 2017 with four sessions listed below.
All events took place at &lt;a href=&#34;https://cafe-kork.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cafe Kork&lt;/a&gt; and were free and open to the public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;tabletalks-archive&#34;&gt;Tabletalks archive&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ttoa-1-diederik-de-koning----agricultural-architecture--land-management&#34;&gt;TToA 1: Diederik de Koning &amp;ndash; Agricultural Architecture &amp;amp; Land Management&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/ttoa/ttoa_1_deKoning.pdf&#34;&gt;TToA 1 event poster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tuesday, 06.12.2016, 18:00&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kork, Lessingstraße 25, 8010 Graz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tabletalk will focus on the role of architect-educators in the design of agricultural buildings and land settlement for the post-war European countryside. The research aims at building up the required body of knowledge for establishing an international discourse on agricultural design as part of the architectural discipline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diederik de Koning graduated cum laude in architecture from Delft University of Technology, and also holds a master’s degree in Environmental and Infrastructure Planning from the University of Groningen. Since the spring of 2013 he has taught a variety of courses at The Berlage Center for Advanced Studies in Architecture and Urban Design in Delft. He now works for the Institute of Architecture and Landscape at Graz University of Technology. He is currently working on his PhD research at the Borders &amp;amp; Territories research group at TU Delft, which deals with agricultural buildings in the post-war European countryside. Results of the research have been presented at conferences in Warsaw and Venice in 2016. In parallel, he runs an independent architecture practice together with Laura van Santen under the name la-di-da (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.la-di-da.nl/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;http://www.la-di-da.nl/&lt;/a&gt;) which was recently included as one of the 33 invited young Dutch and Flemish offices to present their work as part of the 2016 “MAATWERK/MASSARBEIT” exhibition at the Deutsches Architekturmuseum, Frankfurt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ttoa-2----petra-eckhard-the-anti-canon-of-architectural-modernism&#34;&gt;TToA 2 &amp;ndash; Petra Eckhard: The Anti-canon of Architectural Modernism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/ttoa/ttoa_2_eckhard.pdf&#34;&gt;TToA 2 event poster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tuesday, 10.01.2017, 18:00&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kork, Lessingstraße 25, 8010 Graz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In her talk Petra Eckhard will explore architectural structures located in the Western hemisphere which emerged during the second half of the 20th century as an anti-canon of modernist architecture. As manifestations of personal desires and individual creativity, the works analysed have been realised without the burden of economic, functional, temporal or aesthetic restrictions&amp;ndash;aspects which usually accompany architectural practice. In their important function as foils, the anti-canonic works discussed unfold a special relationship to modernist forms, which paradoxically does both counteract and mirror the “greatness” and hubris associated with the modernist canon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Petra Eckhard is a literary and cultural studies scholar at the Institute of Architectural Theory, Art History and Cultural Studies at Graz University of Technology. She studied English and American Studies in New York, Bern and Graz, where she also received her doctorate in 2010. Her fields of interdisciplinary research involve practices of architectural writing, postmodernist works of literature and architecture as well as their cultural implications. She is the author of “Chronotopes of the Uncanny” (2011) and co-editor of Graz Architecture Magazine (GAM). Currently, she is working on her second book which explores the anti-canon of modernist architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ttoa-3-mars-miltiadis-sekulić----metadata-punks&#34;&gt;TToA 3: Mars, Miltiadis, Sekulić &amp;ndash; Metadata Punks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/ttoa/ttoa_3_mars_sekulic_miltiadis.pdf&#34;&gt;TToA 3 event poster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tuesday, 21.03.2017, 18:00&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kork, Lessingstraße 25, 8010 Graz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;../../event/metadata-punks&#34;&gt;Metadata Punks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ttoa-4-christoph-walter-pirker----visual-ontologies-of-the-indefinite&#34;&gt;TToA 4: Christoph Walter Pirker &amp;ndash; Visual Ontologies of the Indefinite&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/ttoa/ttoa_4_pirker.pdf&#34;&gt;TToA 4 event poster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tuesday, 13.06.2017, 18:00&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kork, Lessingstraße 25, 8010 Graz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the epoch of the Anthropocene, human and non-human agencies are entangled in an extensive fabric, which determines the condition of our world. Such fabric is not balanced in a static equilibrium, but conceived as a flowing and intensive coexistence of currents and conditions, which define the expressions of our environment. The Anthropocene not only gains its geological importance by having inscribed the human’s impact in the geological strata of the planet, but similarly by formulating the conception of geological strata as artificial and virtual layers containing a productive, yet unknown potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dynamic of the anthropocenic fabric brings about a new approach to ontogenesis, which no longer occurs by means of substantialist or hylomorphic principles, but through the process of becoming in the intra-action between the natural and the cultural, the conscious and the unconscious, the visible and the invisible. Matter is conceived as a living entity, which intra-acts with the human in complex networks, thereby abolishing traditional hierarchies and dichotomies imposed by the hegemonic system. To investigate such complexity by focusing on the construction of space is the aim of this research, while concurrently rendering visible the overall construction of the anthropocenic fabric.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul Virilio dates the origin of a global overformation with the development of the war landscape. It shows the anthropocenic fabric in its global dimensions, constructing an artificial climate and an ecology wherein the real and the virtual move and continuously flow together. Thereby, the construction of the bunker is seen as the mirror image of such war landscape, no longer being object or artefact, but an integral part or knot within the artificial fabric. Its geological investigation allows to consider the rhythm of the Anthropocene in its totality and to establish its rhythmic material as a tool for future inquiry and research.
In referring to the notion of duration, “Visual ontologies of the indefinite” outlines an intra-acting method, which stands in a geological present and understands the geological relict as an atmospheric particle of our immediate environment. Developing practices of embodiment and intuition, the field of warfare is thus not conceived as a mere historic seclusion, but as vibrating object of investigation for our planetary entanglement, encompassing politics, ideology, space, media, visuality, and art to a cohesive body of action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christoph Walter Pirker (1989) is Assistant professor at the Institute for Architecture and Landscape at the Graz University of Technology. Furthermore, he is trained as an architect, musician, and visual artist. His transdisciplinary interest is based on studies at the University of Music and Performing Arts, Graz, the TU Graz and the Royal Danish Academy of Fine Arts in Copenhagen, Denmark. Highly engaged in practices of performative research, he is currently working on his PhD project (supervised by Milica Tomić) entitled “Visual ontologies of the indefinite &amp;ndash;Investigating spatial relationships of the human, the non-human, and the unknown”. The doctoral thesis is a continuation of the 2015 master thesis, which was awarded the Graz Architecture Diploma Award in October 2016. His work is at studiobirkenblau.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Lecture Series (2015-2019)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/project/iam-open-lectures/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2015 19:00:04 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/project/iam-open-lectures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;IAM Open Lecture Series&lt;/em&gt; was founded in late 2015 at the Institute of Architecture and Media (IAM), TU Graz. The project slowly formalised as a mapping of the research ecology concerning computation and related discourse in the wider field of architecture and media.
The series hosts talks by younger academic researchers and practitioners aiming to present and promote experimental, interdisciplinary and ongoing research.
All sessions are hosted at the New Media Lab of IAM, Kronesgasse 5/III, Graz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;open-lectures-archive&#34;&gt;Open lectures archive&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the documentation of sessions 1-30 see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/iam-open-lectures&#34;&gt;IAM Open Lectures Archive&lt;/a&gt; on this website.
For the complete catalog of the series see &lt;a href=&#34;https://iam.tugraz.at/main-website/category/openlecture/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;IAM Open lectures at iam.tugraz.at&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Video documentation of the &lt;em&gt;IAM Open Lectures&lt;/em&gt; is archived at:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://tube.tugraz.at/paella/ui/browse.html?series=9866b725-a6f2-41ca-8e5c-00879478b22f&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;TU Graz Tube&lt;/a&gt; and on &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/channels/iamlectures&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;IAM Open Lecture&lt;/em&gt; series was founded in late 2015 by Constantinos Miltiadis who curated and produced the first 30 sessions of the series until mid 2019&amp;ndash;except lectures #1 and #15 organized by Urs Hirschberg, and #10 organized by Florian Fend.&lt;br&gt;
Since late 2019, the &lt;em&gt;Open Lectures Series&lt;/em&gt; is carried out by current members of IAM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;filming--production&#34;&gt;Filming &amp;amp; Production&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Department of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tugraz.at/oe/lehr-und-lerntechnologien/home/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Educational Technology&lt;/a&gt;, TU Graz&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;acknowledgements&#34;&gt;Acknowledgements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to Ypatios Grigoriades (TU Graz Educational Technology Unit) for supporting the lecture series throughout the years; to Antonia Manhatsberger and Alexis Kalaitzopoulos who filmed and edited most of the lecture sessions; and to IAM student assistants Nora Hoti, Julian Jauk, Ludwig Grimm, and Martin Schrotz for their help in producing lecture sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
