<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>design research | studio any</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/design-research/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/design-research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>design research</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu4964246c05a61ea2dde1a8350b549fed_585_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>design research</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/design-research/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Architecture and SpaceTimeCraft</title>
      <link>https://example.com/project/spacetimecraft/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/project/spacetimecraft/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Long-term transdisciplinary research project on virtual architecture.
The project investigates the aesthetic experience in virtual spatiotemporal environments that cannot be reproduced in physical reality, through integrative design research.
It is pursued through mixed methods including prototyping, experimental gamemaking, teaching experimental course curricula, media archeology, presenting and publishing; and it interfaces with discourse fields including architecture, game studies, design research, media studies, and artistic research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project started following the development of &lt;a href=&#34;../project-anywhere&#34;&gt;project Anywhere&lt;/a&gt; at the Chair for CAAD at ETH Zurich in 2014. It continued through teaching the experimental course &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/vsms&#34;&gt;Virtual Spaces Master Studio&lt;/a&gt; on VR game design for architects developed and taught at the Institute of Architecture and Media at TU Graz in 2016 and 2017, as well as other short intensive &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/workshop&#34;&gt;workshops&lt;/a&gt;.
In late 2019 the project developed into a doctoral research project at Aalto University, School of Arts, expected in 2025, titled: &lt;em&gt;SpaceTimeCraft: Integrative Research through Design into the Experience of Virtual Navigation&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is a catalog of related publications and presentations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other than Text: Media Used in Game Studies Publications</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/23-digra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 14:23:09 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/23-digra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;publication-history&#34;&gt;Publication history&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I originally wrote this paper in late 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was submitted in January 2022 for the conference &amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design research thesis course</title>
      <link>https://example.com/course/22-design-ba/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 16:43:14 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/course/22-design-ba/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bachelor thesis course tutor and thesis advisor for the English-language &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aalto.fi/en/study-options/design-bachelor-of-arts-master-of-arts-art-and-design&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Design BA&lt;/a&gt; program taught by Oscar Person and Namkyu Chun. Department of Design, Aalto University, School of ARTS, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advisor for the theses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pakarinen, Ilona. ‘Community Driven Anti-Harassment Strategies for MMOGs’. Bachelor Thesis, Aalto University, School of Art and Design, 2022. Aalto ARTS. &lt;a href=&#34;https://urn.fi/URN:NBN:fi:aalto-202207034373&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://urn.fi/URN:NBN:fi:aalto-202207034373&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reti Kilvet. ‘Nudging for Sustainable Fashion Consumption: A Concept Design Based on Expert and Consumer Analysis’. Bachelor Thesis, Aalto University, School of Art and Design, 2022. Aalto ARTS. &lt;a href=&#34;https://urn.fi/URN:NBN:fi:aalto-202301221368&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://urn.fi/URN:NBN:fi:aalto-202301221368&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
